Guide to the Sheek Family Papers, 1767-1939 RL.10088
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sheek family papers
1767-1939, bulk 1850-1869
1850-1869
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sheek family
RL.10088
3.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains mainly letters (mostly between 1850-1869) to members of the Sheek family of North Carolina, from relatives who had migrated to Kentucky, Tennessee, Indiana, Illinois, Iowa, and Texas. The letters concern religion in the West, economic conditions, farming on the frontier, Texas during the 1840s-1860s, sectional strife, Civil War experiences, and conditions in the Confederacy and after the war.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
The Sheek family of North Carolina had many relatives who migrated to Kentucky, Tennessee, Indiana, Illinois, Iowa, and Texas in the mid-nineteenth century.
Provenance
The Sheek family papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1950.
Collection Overview
The collection contains letters to the Sheek, Smith, and Clouse families of North Carolina from relatives who migrated to Tennessee, Kentucky, Illinois, Indiana, and Texas, concerning land and commodity prices; religion; the Mexican War; Trinity College, North Carolina; farming on the frontier; conditions in Texas, 1840-1870; secession in North Carolina; the experiences of several Confederate soldiers; and Reconstruction. The collection also contains advertisements for books and patent medicines North Carolina ballots; circulars for giris' schools and boys' schools in Lockville and Jonesville, North Carolina; bills; receipts; and summonses from a justice of the peace.
Former collection name: Jacob Sheek and Jonathan Smith Papers.
West (U.S.) -- Religion; Confederate States of America -- Social conditions; Migration, Internal -- United States; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives; Land settlement -- West (U.S.); Southern States -- Social conditions; Agriculture -- West (U.S.); West (U.S.) -- Economic conditions; Texas -- Social conditions; Sheek, Jacob; Sheek, Jonathan Smith
- Sheek family papers, 1767-1939
  - Correspondence, 1820-1869; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1870-1929 and undated; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Bills and receipts, 1767-1829; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Bills and receipts, 1820-1839; 4 folder (Box 4)
  - Bills and receipts, 1840-1849; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Bills and receipts, 1850-1899; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Bills and receipts, undated (Box 7)
  - Legal papers and printed materials, undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Weaving drafts and other documents, undated (Box 7)
  - Confederate States of America Post Office, Smith Grove, North Carolina: Accounts of Mails Sent, 1861, 1864 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Daybook (Volume 1)